

#### JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER

A-152, New Ashok Nagar, Delhi - 110096

🛘 (+91) 9911194204 | 🖂 satyamyadav3@gmail.com | 🚱 satyamyadav.info | 👼 satyamyadav | in satyamyadav3 | 💆 Satyam\_yadav

# Summary

I am a software development engineer with more than 2 years of experience in **Frontend Development** and **Javascript**, currently working at a healthcare technology company <u>Innovaccer Inc</u>. I am dedicated to deliver seamless user experiences along with architecting the resilient web applications.

## **Skills**

**Currently focusing** Javascript - Design Patterns, Functional programming and reactive programming

Libraries - React, Redux, Styled

Frameworks - Angularjs, Expressjs, Nodejs

TDD - Jest, Cypress

**Relevant skills** Packaging - Webpack, Gulp, Bower, Docker and Docker-compose

Version Control - Git

Automation - Gitlab CI, Circle CI

**Release Management** - NPM, Semver, Lerna Google Cloud, Amazon Web Services, Heroku,

**Also working with** MongoDB, Redis, nginx, Jira

HTML5, CSS3, sass

# **Work Experience**

Innovaccer Inc.

Noida, India

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER - FRONTEND

Sep. 2016 - PRESENT

- I am working on <u>InConnect</u> with a team strength of ten which include two ui developers and provides omni-channel communication for better engagement of providers with patients through outreach, Two-way secure messaging and **telehealth** support.
- My key areas include understanding business requirements, planning, development, release management, staging deployments of two applications, a mobile web chat application and a SPA for bulk communication both running inside their **docker** environment over **expressjs** and using inhouse frameworks for shell rendering, **react** and **redux** for spa.
- Developing framework agnostic design system using gatsbyjs, sass, lerna and taking care of design inconsistency of the applications which use scoped styles, css in js.
- I am actively involved in helping teams understanding **BFF**, **micro-frontend**, **PRPL** and modular application architecture and inhouse frameworks we have build on top of these priciples, maintaining internal private npm registry using verdaccio and **gitlab CI** for smooth collaboration.
- My past roles include training team to write plugins and scripts for <u>InGraph</u> and migration of dashboards from legacy framework. Developing report automation tool for exporting analytical data in PDF format with data grids and visualizations which can be downloaded to browser, queued for batch processes and written to filesystem or uploaded to a service using expressjs, redis, wkhtmltopdf, **D3js**.
- Developed package management tool for smooth collaboration and integration using git, git submodule, gulp and nodejs (child\_process).

Delhi, India

 Web Developer
 Feb. 2015 - Aug. 2016

- Worked on the social video micro blogging platform **Franklyme**, where I designed and developed embeddable responsive **video widgets** served over expressjs, dashboard to create, preview and get different widgets to be embedded in any web page by user.
- Some of highlights from my role are video-comment widgets (video version of disqus), web video recorder, hiring/audition video widgets wizard, hiring panel, admin/moderation panel.
- Rolled out internal framework on top of express.js, consuming rest APIs on server to build server rendered single page app That provides the look and feel of using modern single page app development frameworks like angularjs, react etc. And with ability to retain easy and regular seo optimization as required by young business idea to gain traction through every channel And on the front-end side using regular jquery.
- Developed end to end web applications for initial evolution of the business idea for young startups like <u>Bummlers</u>, **flatabout** (now your **yourquote**) and revamped **musejam.com** UI.



### **UI Engine**

NODE.JS, EXPRESS, MONGODB, DOCKER, WEBPACK

• Datashop-Engine is an application development framework designed to take care of the connection points between existing popular frameworks and solve common integration problems with MongoDB, Node.js, Express, Web Services adapter and Angular, React, Vue, Mithril (any modern UI framework or lib) based applications. It is designed to give you a quick and organised way to start developing Datashop based web apps.

#### inconnect

Telehealth, Surveys, recordings

· Helping providers to better engage and empower patients to make more informed decisions about their health.

### json-form

FORM BUILDING FRAMEWORK WITH JSON CONFIGURATIONS, USING HTML FORMS.

source

• Technology: javascript (ES6)

#### postgres-express

A BOILERPLATE USING POSTGRESQL AND EXPRESS WITH TDD;

source

• Technology: Express, NoseJS, PostgreSQL, Knex, Tabel, Mocha & chai.

## **Education**

Bachelor of Technology Meerut, India

COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

2012 - 2016

Sir Chhotu Ram Institute of Engineering and Technology,

Chaudhary Charan Singh University Campus

# **Open Learning**

Bengaluru, India

JSF00

Oct. 2018

 Attained jsfoo a javascript conference covering the road ahead in JavaScript and the Web ecosystem, Functional programming Improving performance and UX, Building systems, tools and processes for teams, Case studies of Vue.js, GraphQL, ReasonML and other framework/language adoption.

Bengaluru, India

GDD INDIA

**FOSS** 

Dec. 2017

Attained Google Developers Day, India 2017, A two day event with Codelab and multiple learning sessions on development and technology
like Data-driven PWA, web components, serverless computing, tensorflow and dialogflow.

Delhi, India

ARCHITECTING ON AWS

Jun. 2017

Completed one week AWS training on architecting on AWS which includes cloud computing, serverless architecture (lambda), efficient architecture and load balancing.

Meerut, India

July. 2013 - May. 2016

• Organised and workshops for linux and increasing Awareness towards FOSS in college.

May 13, 2019 Satyam Yadav - Resume 2